Okay, so what is Git? Git is version
control software. It allows you to take
your code, make a copy of it, make some
changes, and then compare the copy to
the original, and then merge the two
together so that you keep the parts you
want to keep of your changes, and you
keep the parts you want to keep of the
original, and everything will still work
smoothly. Um, to show you this in um
action, I'm going to show you a project
that I worked on recently. So, I'm going
to share my screen. And here um you can
see um
this is an example of what Git does. I
added some comments, added some console,
I added a log statement, I sent a
message. Um and over here,
this is the original. Here it's saying,
hey, you added some things. And that's
in green. And saying, here are some
things you removed. And that's in red.
Um you can see it if you compare another
file you can see things I added and
removed. Um so how does it do that? Well
the way it does that is here is
my folder. Um so this is this contains
all of my project. If you click on front
end um you can see all of the app um all
of the files that I used in this
project. So we are in the project. If
you come here and click view on a
windows and then click hidden items,
you'll see that there is a new hidden
item here called get. When you create um
when you start using get, it will start
tracking changes. And it does this with
a hidden folder. In this folder, it has
a whole bunch of files that help it keep
track of what changes you made to which
files. And because it did that, um, it
can show you all of the changes that you
made to this file, when you made them,
who made them, and you can even roll
those changes back. Um,
so right here I can see that I've got
some old changes that I removed, some
new changes that I added. And that is
the power of git.